PIZON SHETU

+1-917-340-3347

pizon.skhan@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pizon-shetu/

www.github.com/izinex/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and motivated learner with experience in data analysis, I can extract meaningful insights and build intuitive models to help with decision making, allowing businesses to grow with their objectives in mind using data-driven solutions.

EDUCATION

Springboard Data Science Bootcamp

Online 2021

Performed and implemented full Python Data Science Stack, Data Wrangling, Statistical Inference, Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning, Deep Learning, SQL, A/B Testing, etc.

Queens College: BA in Computer Science and Applied Math

NY, Queens 2016 - 2020

Relevant Coursework: Statistic, Bayesian Modeling, Linear Algebra, Linear Programming, Machine Learning in R.

TECH STACK

Python: Pandas, NumPy, OOP, SciPy, Statsmodel, Tensorflow, Keras, Flask, requests, PyTorch

Machine Learning: Neural Networks, Regression, Decision Trees, RandomForest Scikit-Learn, OpenCV, R,

Databricks, Classification, RandomForest, NLP, Git

SQL: NoSQL, sql-lite, Microsoft SQL Server, DBMS, ETL, Data Analysis, DML

Apache: Hadoop, PySpark, MongoDB, MapReduce, HDFS, Hbase, Data mining, Oozie, Mahout

Visualization: Tableu, PowerBI, Seaborn, Matplotlib

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Designed and built Convolutional Neural Network for Image Recognition - Classification

- Utilized Keras API to build a complex neural network which can classify 315 different species of birds.
- Leveraged Transfer-Learning with VGG16, it was able to classify with a 94% accuracy.
- Hyper-parameter tuning the model through Bayesian Optimization and freezing/unfreezing CNN layers led to a further gain of 4% and result in 98% accuracy in predictions.

Predictive Pricing Model - Regression Model

- Created a competitive pricing model by analyzing Big Mountain's attractions and facilities to their competitors.
- My model was able to increase their revenue by \$3.4 million.

New York Housing Price Prediction - Decision Tree

- · Cleaned and implemented MICE imputations on over 75K invalid and missing data for Zillow's Housing data
- Provided key insights and underlying distribution into NYC housing market, such as wealth gap, cost of homes, and even migration of native residents
- Build a predictive model using Gradient Boosting algorithms with the XGBoost library

Database for College Classes - SQL

- · Build a relational database for Queens College which schedules and maintains classes for the spring semester.
- · All classes were properly allocated so no two classes had conflict when it came to time and location.
- · Included all course departments and faculty buildings

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Data Scientist

ProMarketingHub 2020 - 2021 Queens, NY

- Managed and stored user data on cloud database, performed daily ETL, data cleaning, and preprocessing.
- Coordinated closely with Sr. & Lead Data Scientists to generate and test hypotheses that align with product engagement.
- Assisted Senior team on building website layout based on customer needs using data-driven methods.
- Collaborated and worked on user login authentication using Flask API implementation.
- Defined real-time customer data needs, evaluated data quality, and determined suitability for use.

Data Analyst

Centerplate 2016 - 2020 Elmont, NY

- Performed data entries, sorting and analysis on over 10K+ client data to assist with customer engagement.
- Increased customer orders by 13% by incentivizing coupons and combo deals
- Analyzed food data to find most popular orders to restructure pricing and maximize company profits.
- Created and presented data visualization of customer habits and other findings to help further growth.